<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>it economics on Nicholas M. Synovic</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/categories/it-economics/</link><description>Recent content in it economics on Nicholas M. Synovic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Nicholas M. Synovic</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 10:16:22 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nsynovic.dev/categories/it-economics/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A summary of Economics of Artificial Intelligence in Cybersecurity by Nir Kshetri</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/economics-of-artificial-intelligence-in-cybersecurity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 10:16:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/economics-of-artificial-intelligence-in-cybersecurity/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-summary-of-economics-of-artificial-intelligence-in-cybersecurity">A summary of &lt;em>Economics of Artificial Intelligence in Cybersecurity&lt;/em>&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nir Kshetri IEEE Computer Volume 55; Issue 4, 2022 DOI [0]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-summary-of-economics-of-artificial-intelligence-in-cybersecurity">A summary of &lt;em>Economics of Artificial Intelligence in Cybersecurity&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary">Summary&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#current-state-of-ai-in-cybersecurity-and-key-areas-being-transformed">Current State of AI in Cybersecurity and Key Areas Being Transformed&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#key-factors-driving-ais-use-in-cybersecurity">Key Factors Driving AI&amp;rsquo;s Use in Cybersecurity&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-shortcomings-limitations-and-challenges">Some Shortcomings, Limitations, and Challenges&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#citations">Citations&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>AI in cybersecurity is a growing market estimated to reach $101.8 billion by
2030.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the internet was designed &lt;strong>without&lt;/strong> security in mind, their exists an
asymmetric where small organizations or individuals can comprise large groups,
companies, or nation states. Therefore, defense mechanisms must be in place to
stop these attacks. Since defendants have access to a large corpus of malware
examples, it is possible to train AI models to defend against attacks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="current-state-of-ai-in-cybersecurity-and-key-areas-being-transformed">Current State of AI in Cybersecurity and Key Areas Being Transformed&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>AI is often faster at detecting malware than humans. Additionally, it is also
faster at containing infected devices on a network than a human. Furthermore, AI
can lower the cost of detecting malware.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traditional antivirus programs rely on a database of malware examples to check
against. However, AI can learn the representations of malware and then find new
malware examples prior to them being added to a database. Thus, it is possible
for AI to stop zero-day vulnerabilities by recognizing the representation of
malware during or prior to the attack.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, security experts recommend taking an augmented intelligence approach
with AI security. This involves a human-AI partnership in identifying and acting
upon threats. This is because current AI techniques are not accurate or advanced
enough to entirely replace a human security professional.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AI has already been used to stop advance attacks from foreign, state run
organizations (i.e., APT41) and more common attacks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AI is already in use to detect anomalies in identity and access security. It is
possible for an AI to monitor and make decisions based off of an accounts
activity. As an example, Facebook uses an AI-powered deep entity classification
(DEC) to determine if an account is fraudulent or not. If so, the account is
removed from Facebook. This tool was used to crack down on fake accounts and
accounts that utilized deep fakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AI cybersecurity software is being used by academic institutions as attackers
are increasingly targeting universities and academic institutions. These tools
have been successful in stopping or preventing cyber threats on students, staff,
and networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-factors-driving-ais-use-in-cybersecurity">Key Factors Driving AI&amp;rsquo;s Use in Cybersecurity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The cost of AI cybersecurity tools is dropping both for consumers and for
enterprises. There exists more publicly available and enterprise-only datasets
for training AI to detect malware. And there is a shortage of cybersecurity
professionals entering the workforce, so AI could be used to address this
shortage of staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="some-shortcomings-limitations-and-challenges">Some Shortcomings, Limitations, and Challenges&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There exists several shortcomings with using AI cybersecurity tools. For
starters, it is difficult to explain what the tool is doing. Security
professionals therefore prefer an, &amp;ldquo;Explainable First, Predictive Second&amp;rdquo; [1]
approach to AI tools. Additionally, AI tools can not make security related
decisions without human interventions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And as AI tools grow in popularity, bias will start to develop within these
tools. This could potentially allow an attacker to exploit this bias and write
malware that is not detected by the tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Furthermore, it is uncertain how AI tools would handle volatile situations, such
as the COVID-19 pandemic. As such, cybersecurity professionals might turn &lt;em>off&lt;/em>
or raise the detection threshold on these tools during such situations,
potentially allowing attacks to slip through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, not all of the necessary data to properly train these tools is
available due to federal regulation. Personally identifying information (PII)
cannot be made publicly available for the purposes of training. Additionally, it
is assumed that large &amp;ldquo;data lakes&amp;rdquo; of Americans exist under the control of
foreign entities. It is therefore possible for an entity to utilize one of these
data lakes to write attacks that would not be detected as the attack is coming
from an American rather than a foreign entity.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="citations">Citations&lt;/h2>
Citations availible at https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/economics-of-artificial-intelligence-in-cybersecurity/</description></item></channel></rss>