<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on Nicholas M. Synovic</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Nicholas M. Synovic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Nicholas M. Synovic</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 10:12:33 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nsynovic.dev/categories/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Age Rule: A Media Consumption Proposal</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/the-age-rule/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 10:12:33 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/the-age-rule/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#were-not-getting-any-younger">We&amp;rsquo;re Not Getting Any Younger&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-age-rule">The Age Rule&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#adapting-the-age-rule">Adapting The Age Rule&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-problem-with-the-age-rule">The Problem With The Age Rule&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="were-not-getting-any-younger">We&amp;rsquo;re Not Getting Any Younger&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As dark and depressing as this may sound, our time on this Earth is limited.
Therefore, we must make the most out of our time here. That could mean going on
adventures, raising a family, starting a business, etc. Truly, what matters is
that you find fulfillment in whatever task you set out to accomplish. But there
is one unifying human task that we all share: the consumption of media.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whether its books, TV shows, movies, or video games, we, as a species, consume a
ton of media year over year. But is the quality of what we are consuming worth
or time? As an example, I spend a lot of my time doom scrolling on Instagram
Reels. Is it a good usage of my time? Absolutely not. But I waste my precious
minutes anyways on that platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-age-rule">The Age Rule&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To alleviate this issue, I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with &lt;strong>The Age Rule&lt;/strong>, a simple set of
rules to optimize my media consumption in my life. It is quite simply:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>My age&lt;/em> determines the amount of &lt;strong>quality media&lt;/strong> that I consume per year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other words, since I am 22 as of writing this, before I turn 23, I should
consume 23 pieces of quality media. For me, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to difficult. If
we measure the media in movies, I&amp;rsquo;ve easily seen 30 movies in the last year. But
movies aren&amp;rsquo;t the only form of media that exists, and that is the beauty of that
rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can replace the word &lt;strong>media&lt;/strong> with any genre or combination of genres that I
want. Maybe media is measured in books, or movies, or movies &lt;em>and&lt;/em> books that
have been turned into said movies. And lets not forget other mainstream forms of
media: video games, anime, scientific papers, blogs, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what makes something quality? To me, that answer is subjective upon what the
experience is. For example, I don&amp;rsquo;t watch cheesy romance films alone because I
don&amp;rsquo;t think they are worth my time. But when I&amp;rsquo;m with my girlfriend, and we are
both watching the movie, laughing at it, and spending time together, all of a
sudden that movie became a quality experience. So I won&amp;rsquo;t try and define quality
here, instead I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it up to you to figure that out.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="adapting-the-age-rule">Adapting The Age Rule&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Age Rule doesn&amp;rsquo;t just apply to media consumption. Maybe donating to &lt;em>your
age&lt;/em> number of charities in a year is fulfilling. Or running &lt;em>your age&lt;/em> number
of miles or 5Ks in a year would be fulfilling. Completing &lt;em>your age&lt;/em> number of
projects in a year is also totally valid as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But regardless of the task you want to complete, the amount of times that you do
said task is determined by your age.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-problem-with-the-age-rule">The Problem With The Age Rule&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The problem with The Age Rule is that it is determined by your age, and the
older you get, the harder it will be to obtain your goals. As I mentioned
earlier, I&amp;rsquo;m 22. Therefore, doing 22 of anything should be easy. But when I&amp;rsquo;m 80
(hopefully), watching 80 movies is going to be far more difficult.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what&amp;rsquo;s the solution?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t have one, yet. As unsatisfying as this is, I also didn&amp;rsquo;t intend this
post to set strict rules or guidelines with respect to The Age Rule. My current
working solution for this problem is that as we mature, so too will the tasks
that we want to accomplish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year, I want to watch 22 quality films. When I&amp;rsquo;m 40, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll want to
visit my parents or siblings 40 times that year. I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet, because I&amp;rsquo;m
not there yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But hopefully the ideas and stories that I consume through media while following
The Age Rule will guide me to create more mature, more insightful, and more
mature tasks for the next year.&lt;/p>
Citations availible at https://nsynovic.dev/posts/the-age-rule/</description></item><item><title>Hugo, Gopher, Gemini, and Annoyances</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/hugo-gopher-gemini-annoyance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 08:38:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/hugo-gopher-gemini-annoyance/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hugo-gopher-gemini-and-annoyances">Hugo, Gopher, Gemini, and Annoyances&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My story with setting up a Gopher and Gemini compatible website powered by
Hugo.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>A little while ago, I wanted to create my own website. I struggle with creating
front ends for websites, so I choose to use the Hugo [0] static site generator
as it has many great themes. Learning Hugo was simple enough since the most
basic sites are just &lt;code>md&lt;/code> content files and &lt;code>TOML&lt;/code> config files. So, after a
brief learning period, I built my website, got it hosted on GitHub Pages [1],
and setup a domain from Google Domains [2] to link to it all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That should be it, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well then I saw these two videos from DistroTube [3] [4] and got interested
in creating and hosting my own Gopher [5] phlog and Gemini [6] capsule. This
is where the annoyances began.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gopher-the-bane-of-my-existence-for-about-a-week">Gopher: The Bane of my Existence (for about a week)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I wanted to create a Gopher phlog because I thought it was just plain cool. Who
wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want a text only mirror of their site not indexed by modern search
engines (probably everyone)? I was aware the Hugo could output my website in a
variety of different formats. But, I had no idea how to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily, Jason F. Betrayer had already figured this out in a blog post on his
website [7]. So I copied and pasted away. I ran the Hugo site generator and I
got output! Huzzah! But when I tested the site with the &lt;code>pernicious&lt;/code> [8]
server, the site was malformed. Links to blog pages lead to nowhere or returned
error message.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I deleted my edits, re-copied, re-pasted (?), and ran the generator. Still,
no dice. Even manually typing in his work into my project didn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point it was getting late, so I put the project into the back of my head
and would continue to work on it for the next week. My stubbornness was because
I knew it was possible to do this conversion, after all, I had gotten output.
But there was a syntax error somewhere that I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t find.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eventually, I found documentation for the &lt;code>gophermap&lt;/code> syntax [9] and it all
clicked. I use &lt;code>Neovim&lt;/code> [10] as my editor of choice. I use spaces instead of
tabs. &lt;code>gophermaps&lt;/code>, as a product of the 90s, require tabs for link formatting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Insert face palm here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fix for this problem was to &lt;code>:set noexpandtab&lt;/code> and then paste in McBrayer&amp;rsquo;s
work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that, the links worked. I then spent some time setting the Gopher template
that he provided to what I wanted, but that was minor work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In all, it took me a week to RTFM and move on from this arguably ridiculous
project.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gemini-a-lot-easier-than-gopher">Gemini: A lot easier than Gopher&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It was significantly easier to create the Gemini capsule than a Gopher Phlog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But before that, I had to create the templates and output settings for Gemini in
Hugo. This, again, was taken care of by Sylvain Durand [11]. With my
&lt;code>:set noexpandtab&lt;/code> option, I copied and pasted his work into my project&amp;hellip; And
boom! It worked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was anticlimactic wasn&amp;rsquo;t it? Again, some formatting of the provided
template was necessary, but that was minor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new problem, was how to distribute this site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pub-nix-whats-old-is-new-again">Pub Nix: What&amp;rsquo;s Old is New Again&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my research of both the Gopher and Gemini protocols, I found out about Pub
Nix: community ran servers that run on low powered machines. These servers are a
modern implementation of the time sharing servers of yore where there were a few
large mainframes in the country that only a few people could log into at a time.
A subset of these Pub Nixs is the &lt;code>tildeverse&lt;/code> [12]. These are &lt;strong>very&lt;/strong>
community oriented servers that offer free web hosting of the Gemini, Gopher,
HTTP, and Spartan sites. All that&amp;rsquo;s required is to create an account and start
uploading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those that are interested in hosting a Gemini and/or Gopher site, I
encourage the usage of these servers as it takes the problems of hosting content
(maintenance, privacy, port forwarding, etc.) off of your shoulders&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-end">The End&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you ware interested in doing something similar, here is a link to my websites
source code on GitHub [13]. There you can see my templates, scripts, and
config options for generating Gemini, Gopher and HTTP sites. Best of luck, and
happy hacking!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="citations">Citations&lt;/h2>
Citations availible at https://nsynovic.dev/posts/hugo-gopher-gemini-annoyance/</description></item><item><title>Why Sign Commits?</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/why-sign-commits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 15:38:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/why-sign-commits/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="why-sign-commits">Why Sign Commits?&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Why should you sign your commits?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="preface">Preface&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I recently read this article [0] by Alessandro Segala about why I should sign
my commits. And I completely agree with, and would like to expand upon, their
work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="identify-theft">Identify Theft&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Identify theft is not a joke [1].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The FTC in their 2021 edition of the CSN Annual Data Book [2] reported that
there were 1,434,676 reports of identity fraud in 2021 This theft allows the
perpetrator to commit acts of fraud in your name while reaping the benefits. As
developers, we not only have to protect our real world identities from theft,
but our digital ones as well. And while it is important to have strong and
secure passwords, I&amp;rsquo;m not referring to your accounts as digital identities. I&amp;rsquo;m
instead talking about your contributions to open source projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article focuses around &lt;code>git&lt;/code> [3] and online version control systems
(VCSs) that implement &lt;code>git&lt;/code> as their back end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is not only possible, but incredibly easy to sign a commit under a different
identity. In addition, online VCSs will read the &lt;code>git&lt;/code> commit history and per
commit, add the appropriate account information to the commit (assuming an
account exists with the email address that is attached to the &lt;code>git&lt;/code> repository).
This feature, is meant to provide a user friendly way of viewing &lt;code>git&lt;/code> commits.
However, it also allows for an attacker to take advantage of these tools and
publish commits to a project under someone else&amp;rsquo;s identity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-dangers-of-developer-identity-theft">The Dangers of Developer Identity Theft&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The biggest threat to a developer who doesn&amp;rsquo;t sign their commits is the lack of
trust a community can have for a particular developer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A malicious attacker who signs off on infected, poorly written, or malformed
commits and publishes to a project can ruin a developer&amp;rsquo;s relationship to a
community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A malicious attacker could publish commits that actively ruin existing features.
They could also introduce bugs into a repository under someone&amp;rsquo;s name.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="benefits-of-signing">Benefits of Signing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To combat this, &lt;code>git&lt;/code> allows for individuals to sign their commits with a GPG
[4] key.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This allows for a number of benefits:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Commits in the &lt;code>git&lt;/code> history that are signed have metadata attached to them
saying that they&amp;rsquo;re signed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the GPG key is published to an online VCS that supports this feature, a
&lt;em>verified&lt;/em> tag will be applied to commits that are signed and match a user&amp;rsquo;s
GPG key.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developer identity can be confirmed by running checks against the public
facing key of a commit and a developer&amp;rsquo;s private key.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since reading [0], I have implemented commit signing for my project going
forward. I also now require all group projects to have signed commits prior to
acceptance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Setting up signed commits was trivial, and there were plenty of guides [0]
[5] [6] on how to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I strongly encourage all developers to sign their commits in order to improve
the verification of work done by legitimate developers, instead of allowing the
work of thieves to perforate throughout our community.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="citations">Citations&lt;/h2>
Citations availible at https://nsynovic.dev/posts/why-sign-commits/</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 19:47:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hello-world">Hello World&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An introduction to me, this site, and the content I want to make.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="hi-there">Hi there!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My name is Nicholas M. Synovic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the time of writing, I&amp;rsquo;m a Research Assistant at Loyola University Chicago
[0] with the Software and Systems Laboratory [1]. I graduated Loyola in May
of 2022 with a B.S in Computer Science. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m pursuing a M.S in
Computer Science with a concentration in Artificial Intelligence. My
concentration is more specifically targeting low power computer vision systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an undergrad, I pursued and lead Software Engineering Metrics research and
was successfully able to publish a paper into the IEEE ASE 2022 [2]
conference&amp;rsquo;s tools track as the lead author [3]. In addition, I was fortunate
enough to be an author on a Software Engineering paper focusing on deep learning
model reuse with researchers from Purdue University [4]. I currently work on
both Software Engineering and Computer Vision research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to my academic work, I have experience leading IT teams and
developing full stack software. I was one of the first in my high school to join
the student IT program which performed real world maintenance on my district&amp;rsquo;s
network, personal, and tech infrastructure [5]. As a 2nd year student at
Loyola, I won second place at the Fall Student Showcase for my work in
identifying and providing solution for Congress.gov&amp;rsquo;s search functionality as
well as creating a dataset of all the content on Congress.gov [6]. And as a
4th year senior, I developed an application for Medline Industries [7] to
facilitate their corporate wide Talent Planning Process. This application was
used to assess ~30,000 employees in 2022 to find the next generation of leaders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the social side of things, I am currently a board member of the Loyola AI
Club [8] as well as a student ambassador for Intel&amp;rsquo;s oneAPI platform [9].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For further information on how to contact me, see my Contact page [10].&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-up-with-this-site">What&amp;rsquo;s up with this site?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This site is generated from Markdown using Hugo [11] and the Ananke theme
[12].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This decision was made due to Hugo&amp;rsquo;s extensive templating feature, which allows
me to accessible to those using HTTP [13], Gopher [14], and Gemini [15]
protocols. I intend to use this site to experiment with other alternative
network protocols as they are developed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This site is also mirrored across several different services. Currently, it is
hosted on both GitHub Pages [16] as &lt;code>https://nsynovic.dev&lt;/code> [17]. Blog posts
are mirrored on my the Gopher and Gemini versions of this site, as well as my
Dev.to [18] page. In addition, I intend to use my account at &lt;code>tilde.team&lt;/code>
[19] to add an additional backup of the HTTP site there as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-content-is-coming">What content is coming?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t have a set plan at the moment, however, I intend to provide less
academically leaning posts on this site. Think more opinion pieces, tutorials,
or other ramblings. Primarily text based content will be posted on this site as
there are other platforms that are better at hosting multimedia content.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="citations">Citations&lt;/h2>
Citations availible at https://nsynovic.dev/posts/hello-world/</description></item></channel></rss>