<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mobile communication on Nicholas M. Synovic</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/categories/mobile-communication/</link><description>Recent content in Mobile communication on Nicholas M. Synovic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Nicholas M. Synovic</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 12:31:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nsynovic.dev/categories/mobile-communication/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A summary of Multimedia Content Creation using Global Network Cameras: The Making of CAM2 by Ahmed S. Kaseb et al.</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/mulitmedia-content-creation-using-global-network-cameras-the-making-of-cam2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 12:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/mulitmedia-content-creation-using-global-network-cameras-the-making-of-cam2/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-summary-of-multimedia-content-creation-using-global-network-cameras-the-making-of-cam2">A summary of &lt;em>Multimedia Content Creation using Global Network Cameras: The Making of CAM2&lt;/em>&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ahmed S. Kaseb et al. GlobalSIS, 2015 DOI [0]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>DISCLOSURE&lt;/strong>: I work with one of the authors (Yung-Hsiang Lu). My comments and
views of the paper may be skewed due to my relationship with the author.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the summary of the paper, go to the &lt;a href="#summary">Summary&lt;/a> section of this
article.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-summary-of-multimedia-content-creation-using-global-network-cameras-the-making-of-cam2">A summary of &lt;em>Multimedia Content Creation using Global Network Cameras: The Making of CAM2&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#first-pass">First Pass&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#problem">Problem&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#motivation">Motivation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#category">Category&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#context">Context&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#contributions">Contributions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#second-pass">Second Pass&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#background-work">Background Work&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#figures-diagrams-illustrations-and-graphs">Figures, Diagrams, Illustrations, and Graphs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#clarity">Clarity&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#relevant-work">Relevant Work&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#methodology">Methodology&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#author-assumptions">Author Assumptions&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#correctness">Correctness&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#future-directions">Future Directions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#open-questions">Open Questions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#author-feedback">Author Feedback&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#summarization-technique">Summarization Technique&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#citations">Citations&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="first-pass">First Pass&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Read the title, abstract, introduction, section and sub-section headings, and
conclusion&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There exists many cameras in the wild that are openly exposing their feeds to
the interent intended or otherwise. It is therefore possible to create a
database of these open cameras, access their feeds, and create new content
experiences for viewers. Additionally, these feeds provide researchers with an
opportunity to view real world changes longitudinally, thereby enabling studies
that rely on many observations over time. This database and tooling is called
CAM2 (Continuous Analysis of Many CAMeras), and it currently contains 70,000
cameras in the wild.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, managing and providing a dataset of all this data is difficult.
Furthermore, finding and reporting camera metadata including make and model as
well as geographic location are also non-trivial tasks. Thus CAM2 is working
towards resolving these issues for future revisions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="problem">Problem&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What is the problem addressed in the paper?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>THe problem addressed in the paper is that there exists a spot in content
creation and research to use the camera feeds of openly exposed devices to
create new experiences and insights into the world around us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, trying to capture this data requires a significant amount of
engineering and computational resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivation">Motivation&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Why should we care about this paper?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Because it provides a tool to allow for the creation of new content experiences
and research opportunities using open, internet exposed cameras.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, it provides a list of problems that reimplementers and extenders
will face when trying to recreate similar tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="category">Category&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What type of paper is this work?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a tools paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="context">Context&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What other &lt;em>types&lt;/em> of papers is the work related to?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This paper is related to work involving using open, internet exposed web cameras
for creating new experiences and research opportunities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="contributions">Contributions&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What are the author&amp;rsquo;s main contributions?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A tool to provide easy access to the internet exposed web cameras.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="second-pass">Second Pass&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A proper read through of the paper is required to answer this&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="background-work">Background Work&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What has been done prior to this paper?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Prior work has gone through the effort of collecting information from open,
internet cameras. However, the compute and storage complexity has limited their
usefulness. Furthermore, in order to make this tool useful to all researchers,
as a cloud software technology, autoscaling and load balancing is a challenge as
well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="figures-diagrams-illustrations-and-graphs">Figures, Diagrams, Illustrations, and Graphs&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Are the axes properly labeled? Are results shown with error bars, so that
conclusions are statistically significant?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>All of the images are properly labelled.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="clarity">Clarity&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Is the paper well written?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes, the paper is well written.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="relevant-work">Relevant Work&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Mark relevant work for review&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The following relevant work can be found in the &lt;a href="#citations">Citations&lt;/a> section
of this article.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Image-Based Geographical Location Estimation Using Web Cameras [2]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>IP Geolocation Databases: Unreliable? [3]&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="methodology">Methodology&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What methodology did the author&amp;rsquo;s use to validate their contributions?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>They created a tool to allow for the analysis of many cameras continously. There
was no validation mentioned w.r.t any experiments that they ran. Additionally,
source code is not provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="author-assumptions">Author Assumptions&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What assumptions does the author(s) make? Are they justified assumptions?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The only assumption that the authors make is that the cameras will remain
accessible after the publication of the paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="correctness">Correctness&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Do the assumptions seem valid?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>No it is not a valid assumption because the owners of these open, internet
connected cameras could becgin to password protect their cameras for privacy or
security concerns, thus making the usage of this tool limited or non-optimal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="future-directions">Future Directions&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My own proposed future directions for the work&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Currently, this tool is no longer functional at the URL the author&amp;rsquo;s provide. It
would be cool to recreate portions of this tool. Additionally, figuring out
optimal ways of discovering internet connected cameras would be interesting as
well. Furthermore, learning how to geo-locate IP addresses is also interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="open-questions">Open Questions&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What open questions do I have about the work?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>How does one get access to the dataset described by the authors?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="author-feedback">Author Feedback&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What feedback would I give to the authors?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a pretty good tools paper. However, like many tools papers, without
source code or long-term data archival, this work cannot be easily extended
upon.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="summarization-technique">Summarization Technique&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This paper was summarized using a modified technique proposed by S. Keshav in
his work &lt;em>How to Read a Paper&lt;/em> [0].&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="citations">Citations&lt;/h2>
Citations availible at https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/mulitmedia-content-creation-using-global-network-cameras-the-making-of-cam2/</description></item></channel></rss>