<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>responsible conduct in research on Nicholas M. Synovic</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/categories/responsible-conduct-in-research/</link><description>Recent content in responsible conduct in research on Nicholas M. Synovic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Nicholas M. Synovic</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 12:48:53 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nsynovic.dev/categories/responsible-conduct-in-research/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A summary of On Being a Scientist: A Guide To Responsible Conduct In Research by the National Academy of Science, National Academy of Engineering and Institute of Medicine of the National Academies</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/on-being-a-scientist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 12:48:53 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/on-being-a-scientist/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-summary-of-on-being-a-scientist-a-guide-to-responsible-conduct-in-research">A summary of &lt;em>On Being a Scientist: A Guide To Responsible Conduct In Research&lt;/em>&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Written by the National Academy of Science, National Academy of Engineering
and Institute of Medicine of the National Academies&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-summary-of-on-being-a-scientist-a-guide-to-responsible-conduct-in-research">A summary of &lt;em>On Being a Scientist: A Guide To Responsible Conduct In Research&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#chapter-summaries">Chapter Summaries&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-national-academies-advisors-to-the-nation-on-science-engineering-and-medicine">The National Academies Advisors to the Nation on Science, Engineering, and Medicine&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#preface">Preface&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-note-on-using-on-being-a-scientist">A Note on Using &lt;em>On Being a Scientist&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#introduction-to-the-responsible-conduct-of-research">Introduction to the Responsible Conduct of Research&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#advising-and-mentoring">Advising and Mentoring&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#treatment-of-data">Treatment of Data&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#mistakes-and-negligence">Mistakes and Negligence&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#research-misconduct">Research Misconduct&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#responding-to-suspected-violations-of-professional-standards">Responding to Suspected Violations of Professional Standards&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#human-participants-and-animal-subjects-in-research">Human Participants and Animal Subjects in Research&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#laboratory-safety-in-research">Laboratory Safety in Research&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#sharing-of-research-results">Sharing of Research Results&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#authorship-and-the-allocation-of-credit">Authorship and the Allocation of Credit&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#intellectual-property">Intellectual Property&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#competing-interests-commitments-and-values">Competing Interests, Commitments, and Values&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-researcher-in-society">The Researcher in Society&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#citations">Citations&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="chapter-summaries">Chapter Summaries&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Chapter specific summaries&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="the-national-academies-advisors-to-the-nation-on-science-engineering-and-medicine">The National Academies Advisors to the Nation on Science, Engineering, and Medicine&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>National Academy of Science&lt;/strong> (NAS) (created in 1863) is a private,
non-profit, self-perpetuating society of distinguished scholars that are
required to advise the federal government on scientific and technical matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>National Academy of Engineers&lt;/strong> (NAE) (created in 1964) is a parallel
organization to NAS that also advises the federal government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Institute of Medicine&lt;/strong> (created in 1970) is a subsidiary of NAS aimed at
advising the government about public health policy matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>National Research Council&lt;/strong> was created in 1916 to broadly advise on
research matters. It is now the primary concern of both NAS and NAE.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="preface">Preface&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Science is built upon trust. When trust is misplaced and professional standards
are violated, researchers feel attacked and that the base of their profession
has been undermined.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many new researchers are not learning about how to conduct themselves as
scientists (a broad definition that includes anyone who is involved with the
pursuit of knowledge). This task used to be placed on more senior researchers.
However, as the speed of scientific developments, this task is often placed on
the back burner. Furthermore, exciting opportunities keep appearing faster than
science can keep up, further contributing to the problem of not educating new
researchers on best practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Senior researchers have a special responsibility of upholding and promulgating
high standards in science. They should be role models, teachers, and mentors to
junior researchers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-note-on-using-on-being-a-scientist">A Note on Using &lt;em>On Being a Scientist&lt;/em>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This book explores options for handling situations, not defining what exactly to
do in a particular situation. This book should be read by a group of researchers
that discuss the topics within and figure out how to apply the lessons to their
practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The material within this book is not exhaustive, and many texts and websites now
exist to help supplement this material.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The existence of professional standards implies that there is a proper way to go
about a task or field. However, this book doesn&amp;rsquo;t aim to cover specifics. To
address specific concerns, a committee consisting of a diverse group of
individuals from varying experience levels should be formed to identify and
discuss what is the professional standards. Furthermore, if your professional
has an established code of conduct or professional standards, those should be
referred to for specifics.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="introduction-to-the-responsible-conduct-of-research">Introduction to the Responsible Conduct of Research&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Researchers pride themselves on observing or explaining phenomenon which haven&amp;rsquo;t
been seen or explained previously. However, researchers are often under a great
deal of personal and professional pressure. Failure to properly collect, report,
or handle data, experiments, or papers can result in lost time, money, and
respect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Researchers have thus created professional standards over many centuries for
many different fields. It is therefore expected that researchers will adhere to
these standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus there is an obligation to honor the trust that their colleagues place in
them and vice versa. Irresponsible actions of others could potentially undermine
an entire field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is also an obligation for researchers to conduct themselves in a
responsible manner or else face potentially permanent damage to their
reputation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, researchers have an obligation to the public. It is their results
that effect public policy which affects everyone. Additionally, their results
may have a butterfly effect that affects international peoples or policy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A &lt;em>scientific standard&lt;/em> is the application of the ethical values of honesty,
fairness, objectivity, openness, trustworthiness, and respect for others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Scientific misconduct&lt;/em> is defined as, &amp;ldquo;fabrication, falsification or plagiarism
in proposing, performing, or reviewing researcher, or in reporting research
results,&amp;rdquo; by the US government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those that operate with &lt;em>scientific misconduct&lt;/em> are said to work with
&lt;em>questionable research practices&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>scientific standard&lt;/em> proliferates throughout the entirety of science, but
&lt;em>scientific practices&lt;/em> (application of standards) differs from field to field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="advising-and-mentoring">Advising and Mentoring&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It is often best to build a diverse community of mentors as not one person has
the same experience, education, or background as another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being a mentor is not a one way street where the mentee only benefits. As a
mentor, you experience the benefits of being exposed to new ideas, building a
strong research program and collaboration network, and gain new friends plus
respect from beginning researchers. However, mentors have influence over the
start of a junior researcher&amp;rsquo;s career, and must therefore be careful not to
abuse it. The main role of the mentor is to help the mentee move along a
productive and successful career trajectory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mentees also have responsibilities towards their mentors. They need to develop
clear expectations regarding meeting times and availability with their mentors,
and need to seek out their mentors, rather than expect a mentor to be provided
to them. For more information on this subject, please read &lt;em>Adviser, Teacher,
Role Model, Friend: On Being a Mentor to Students in Science and Engineering&lt;/em> by
Philip A. Grififths [1].&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="treatment-of-data">Treatment of Data&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Researchers who maliciously manipulate data to deceive others violate the basic
values and accepted professional standards of science. In doing so they mislead
colleagues, potentially impede progress in their field, undermine their own
authority and trustworthiness, and they introduce misinformation into both the
scientific record and the public sphere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To ensure the integrity of science, researchers have developed and continually
improve upon methods such as statistical tests of significance, double-blind
trials, and proper survey phrasing ensured by the academic&amp;rsquo;s relevant Internal
Review Board (IRB). Because it is paramount that the integrity of the work is
valid, papers must include a description of the methodology used to generate the
data. This is because if the methodology to generate the data is incorrect or
not present, then the integrity of the data and the work can be called into
question. Furthermore, this helps ensure the reproducibility of science.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New researchers are not trained on how to generate, share, store, and publish
data. Additionally, new technologies to store, transmit, generate, and analyze
data are constantly being created. Thus researchers face a dilemma of how to
store data permanently so that it can be used in future works (either by
themselves or with others). However, when academic works are released the data
must be made available. If a researcher refuses to share the data, then they
fail to maintain the standards of science.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mistakes-and-negligence">Mistakes and Negligence&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>All science is susceptible to error. However, researchers have an obligation to
be as accurate and as careful as possible both for their profession and the
public.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make progress, researchers must believe the works of other researchers. It is
well known that by, &amp;ldquo;looking for an answer&amp;rdquo;, or believing that there exists an
answer prior to running experiments, that researchers bias themselves to believe
that something exists when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. However, these inaccuracies and mistakes
must be remedied in the scientific record as soon as they are identified so as
to allow the continue proliferation of science.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="research-misconduct">Research Misconduct&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Scientific misconduct, as defined by the U.S. Office of Science and Technology
Policy, defines it as, &amp;ldquo;fabrication, falsification, or plagiarism in proposing,
performing, or reviewing research, or in reporting research results&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The specific definitions for fabrication, falsification, and plagiarism (FFP)
are listed below (and taken from the text):&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Fabrication is &amp;#34;making up data or results.&amp;#34;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Falsification is &amp;#34;manipulating research materials, equipment, or processes, or
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>changing or omitting data or results such that the research is not accurately
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>represented in the research record.&amp;#34;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Plagiarism is &amp;#34;the appropriation of another person&amp;#39;s ideas, processes,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>results, or words without giving appropriate credit.&amp;#34;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Furthermore, misconduct actions significantly depart from accepted practices,
that they were intended, or knowingly, or recklessly, and have to be proven by a
preponderance of information. However, identifying the intent to deceive is
difficult to do, as honest mistakes could also result in the same generated
data. Thankfully, differences of opinion are not scientific misconduct.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To reduce scientific misconduct, co-authors should validate each others work, as
well as have third parties review their results prior to publication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Misconduct can set back individuals, institutions, and research fields. It can
also draw the eye of the public and policy makers to make decisions that are
negative for the progression of science.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="responding-to-suspected-violations-of-professional-standards">Responding to Suspected Violations of Professional Standards&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Science typically self-regulates itself. It is the research community that sets
the standards and practices that researchers should follow. However, as it is
self-regulating, confrontation does occur where results are questioned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When raising these questions, retaliation can occur. However, this is prohibited
by the laws do exist to prevent this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All research institutions that receive federal funding must have methods to
investigate and report misconduct. Anyone who is aware of misconduct must follow
these procedures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All scientists and research institutions should discourage questionable research
practices (QRPs). Additionally, they need to take responsibility in determining
what QRPs warren reprimands from the institution. However, not all fields define
QRPs the same. The act of salami-publishing (deliberately dividing research
results across multiple papers) is viewed differently from field to field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To raise suspicions, ask neutral questions rather than be accusatory. Another
option is to talk to a friend or advisor who can keep the situation
confidential. While this won&amp;rsquo;t necessarily result in changes, this will at least
structure your thinking in what to do next. Another option is to talk to the
research integrity officer who must be appointed if the institution receives
federal funding. However, keep in mind your own motivations and biases prior to
raising questions so as to be courteous and kind.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="human-participants-and-animal-subjects-in-research">Human Participants and Animal Subjects in Research&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Any research done on humans or animals is subject to federal, state, local, and
institutional regulations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The U.S. federal regulations on experiments that involve humans is known as the
Common Rule. The Common Rule specifies exactly what falls under the domain of
human participation in experiments. Furthermore, any research institution
receiving federal grants must have an IRB. The job of the IRB is to ensure that
all research involving human participants follows the Common Rule. Many private
institutions also have IRBs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In some cases where human participation is required, formal training in
bioethics is needed to identify if the experiment is ethical towards the
participants. These issues are often evaluated by the committee&amp;rsquo;s such as the
President&amp;rsquo;s Council on Bioethics in the United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Animals also have federal protections with regard to animal participation in
experiments. The U.S. federal Animal Welfare Act seeks, &amp;ldquo;to insure that animals
intended for use in research facilities &amp;hellip; are provided humane care and
treatment.&amp;rdquo; The U.S. Public Health Service&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Policy on the Human Care and Use
of Laboratory Animals&lt;/em> applies to all research supported by the National
Institute of Health (NIH). This requires institutions, &amp;ldquo;to establish and
maintain proper measures to ensure the appropriate care and use of all animals
involved in research, research training, and biological testing.&amp;rdquo; The policy
requires adherence to both the Animal Welfare Act and NIH&amp;rsquo;s continually updated
&lt;em>Guide for the Care and Use of Laboratory Animals&lt;/em>. This requires that all
animal testing follows the three R&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Reduction in the number of animals used,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Refinement of techniques and procedures to reduce pain and distress,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Replacement of conscious living higher animals with insentient material
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Overseeing the ethical experimentation on animals is an institution&amp;rsquo;s
Institutional Animal Care and Use Committees (IACUCs).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="laboratory-safety-in-research">Laboratory Safety in Research&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Researchers should review safety information and procedures at least once a
year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A shortlist of topics to review includes:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Appropriate usage of protective equipment and clothing,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Safe handling of materials in laboratories,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Safe operation of equipment,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Safe disposal of materials,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Safety management and accountability,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Hazard assessment processes,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Safe transportation of materials between laboratories,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Safe design of facilities,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Emergency responses,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Safety education of all personnel before entering the laboratory,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Applicable government regulations
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h3 id="sharing-of-research-results">Sharing of Research Results&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the 17th century, researchers kept their results secret in order to protect
their results from others claiming them. To solve this, Henry Oldenburg (the
secretary for the Royal Society of London) started to guarantee that not only
researchers could have their results rapidly published, but that the Royal
Society would defend authors integrity. He furthermore invented the modern
review practice of sending out manuscripts to experts prior to publication for
review.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To publish in a peer-reviewed journal is often the most important way to share
information among researchers. This is because the first to publish often gets
the credit. Once results are published, others can cite the author in their
work. Unpublished manuscripts under review are to be treated as confidential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Citations need to be scrutinized during the peer-review process in order to
assess their validity and usefulness. Researchers have a duty to thoroughly
search the available literature on a subject and attribute all relevant authors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Information can be disseminated through seminars, conferences, abstracts, and
posters as well as peer-reviewed journal papers. Often considered to be
preliminary in nature. Spreading data, results, or manuscripts that haven&amp;rsquo;t been
peer-reviewed online is possible as well. However, by bypassing traditional
quality assurance measures, researchers take on a risk that their work won&amp;rsquo;t
serve science well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Publishing or announcing results prior to peer-review is dangerous. Without the
peer-review checks, it is possible for misinformation to be misinterpreted by
the public, policy makers, and other researchers as fact. Additionally, by
posting information prior to a journal submission online, it can be considered
to be a &amp;ldquo;prior publication&amp;rdquo;, thus making it unusable for publishing within the
journal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Publication abuses are possible. For example, researchers may publish the &amp;ldquo;least
publishable unit&amp;rdquo; of information. This is when the smallest number of results
are collected or written about to be published, rather than undergoing an
intensive research process. This wastes the time and energy of reviewers and can
give the researcher a reputation of producing shoddy or incomplete work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="authorship-and-the-allocation-of-credit">Authorship and the Allocation of Credit&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When a paper is published, all of those that contributed to the paper are
considered authors and should be listed as such. Authorship conventions and
practices differ from field to field, and even lab to lab. Open and honest
conversations about how authorship is handled is paramount to ensure that
everyone knows the rules for the author list order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honorary authors (those that contributed zero to little actual content to the
research) should not be added in the author list. They can be acknowledged in an
&amp;ldquo;Acknowledgment&amp;rdquo; section however. Additionally, ghost-writers should not be used
to write a paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All authors on a paper must take responsibility for the content of the paper and
must be able to answer questions about the research.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="intellectual-property">Intellectual Property&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Researchers should be aware of the potential monetary value that their
intellectual property has. Intellectual property is a legal right to control the
application of an idea within a specific context (through a patent) or control
the expression of an idea (through a copyright).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Patent owners can protect [their] intellectual property rights by excluding
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>others from making, using, or selling an invention so long as the patent owner
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>provides a full description of how the invention is made, is used, and
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>functions.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>- Copyrights protect the expression or presentation of ideas, but they do not
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>protect the ideas themselves.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Most research institutions have policies that detail how intellectual policy
rights should be handled. Additionally, patent and copyright laws differ from
country to country. Publication of work should not be delayed because of a
potential patent though.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="competing-interests-commitments-and-values">Competing Interests, Commitments, and Values&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Conflict of interest refers to situations where researchers have personal,
intellectual, financial, and professional interests that conflict with the
ongoing research. Conflicts of financial interests undergo much scrutiny. Should
research be done with a known conflict of financial interest, it severely
damages the researcher&amp;rsquo;s credibility and integrity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Personal relationships can also conflict with research. Often journals and
funding agencies ask for personal relationships in order to identify potential
conflict of personal interests. Romantic relationships often count as a personal
conflict of interest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Timely and full disclosure of conflict of interests must be made to governing
bodies of science when requested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conflicts of commitment are different than conflict of interests. This can cause
significant strain on a researcher&amp;rsquo;s life and should be identified early.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The values that a researcher has can cause a conflict of interest as well.
Religious, philosophical, cultural, or political beliefs can all cause conflicts
of interests. Values cannot and should not be separated from science, but should
be acknowledged and understood while conducting science.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-researcher-in-society">The Researcher in Society&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Researchers have the duty to ensure that not only does their work further
science, but also improves the public&amp;rsquo;s welfare. They are put into an
interesting situation within the public sphere and may have to wear many hats.
However, it is paramount that they remain honest, fair, collegial, and open in
society as these are all core scientific tenants that researchers should follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="citations">Citations&lt;/h2>
Citations availible at https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/on-being-a-scientist/</description></item></channel></rss>