<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Nicholas M. Synovic</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Nicholas M. Synovic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Nicholas M. Synovic</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 21:29:53 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nsynovic.dev/posts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Altweb Journey: Part 0</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/altweb-journey-part0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 12:48:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/altweb-journey-part0/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-altweb-journey-part-0">My Altweb Journey: Part 0&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>What the heck is the altweb?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This question has lead me down a rabbit hole of network protocols, computer
ethics, philosophies on the internet, and enlightenment. Ok, maybe not
enlightenment, but it definitely has exposed me to a whole side of computing
that I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But before I go into this potentially long and rambling post, let me say one
thing:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Don&amp;rsquo;t panic.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seriously, what I&amp;rsquo;m about to describe is not a new version of the internet, your
boss most likely won&amp;rsquo;t bother you with this question ever, and your job is still
safe if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of this before. The altweb (as people are now calling
it) is an attempt at a simpler internet at its core.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now what does that mean?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-altweb-a-macro-view">The Altweb: A Macro View&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The altweb is a collection of &lt;em>decentralized&lt;/em> networks that are powered by niche
network protocols, focussed around peer to peer sharing. Compare that to today,
where Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure, and AWS dominate the web hosting scene.
These companies power 61% of the modern Internet&amp;rsquo;s web services [1]. This
majority stakehold in providing the hosting, compute, and techical services for
powering the Internet has led to these companies centralizing data to their
servers. Because of this centralization, there are serious privacy concerns
[2].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To address these security concerns, there has been a growign movement to bring
back the decentralized web where individuals host data instead of these
companies. Protocols such as &lt;code>Gopher&lt;/code> [3], &lt;code>Gemini&lt;/code> [4], &lt;code>BitTorent&lt;/code> [5],
&lt;code>Hypercore&lt;/code> [6], and &lt;code>IPFS&lt;/code> [7] all try to address this challenge. Now,
there is no reason why Google, Microsoft, or Amazon couldn&amp;rsquo;t come out tomorrow
offering to host &lt;code>gopher&lt;/code> sites for example. After all, these are just web
protocols that anyone with the right software can utilize.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But to make alternatives to these big players and put web hosting back into the
people, Fediverse software [8] is being developed to introduce people to
decentralized social media. In this case, the fediverse is predominately a
collection of social media sites that rely on protocols such as &lt;code>diaspora&lt;/code>
[9], &lt;code>Zot&lt;/code> [10], &lt;code>ActivityPub&lt;/code> [11], and &lt;code>OStatus&lt;/code> [12] to power their
backends. For more traditional apps, decentralized apps (dapps) [13] powered
by blockchain exist. And for those looking for a decentralized database, &lt;code>gun&lt;/code>
[14] and similar databases now exist as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The point in all of this is that each one of these protocols, database schemes,
social media sites, and blockchain technologies exist in their own unique
spheres. As an example, there isn&amp;rsquo;t software out there that combines the power
of the blockchain with &lt;code>gopher&lt;/code>. But that&amp;rsquo;s ok for now. All of this is still in
its infancy with potential to grow into something larger.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="citations">Citations&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/011316/what-amazon-web-services-and-why-it-so-successful.asp">What Is Amazon Web Services and Why Is It So Successful?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.bitsbook.com/">Blown to Bits&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gopher_(protocol)">Gopher (protocol)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://gemini.circumlunar.space/">Project Gemini&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent">BitTorrent&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://hypercore-protocol.org/">Hypercore&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ipfs.io/">IPFS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fediverse.party/en/fediverse/">About Fediverse&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/diaspora/diaspora_federation">diaspora/diaspora_federation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://zotlabs.org/help/en/developer/zot_protocol">What is Zot?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://activitypub.rocks/">ActivityPub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/OStatus">OStatus&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ethereum.org/en/dapps/#what-are-dapps">Decentralized applications (dapps)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://gun.eco/">gun&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m doing the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23100daystooffload&amp;amp;src=typed_query">#100DaysToOffload&lt;/a> challenge.
Check &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nick_synovic">my Twitter&lt;/a> for updates!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Note Taking and Graph DBs</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/graphs-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/graphs-obsidian/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="note-taking-and-graph-dbs">Note Taking and Graph DBs&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I enjoy note taking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that taking notes all the time not only is a good habit, but reduces the
mental energy in trying to remember everything and anything. In tech terms, it
takes a significantly smaller footprint to store a pointer (location of a note)
in memory than everything within that note. This way, if someone says, &amp;ldquo;Hey
remember that thing last week&amp;rdquo;, I can say, &amp;ldquo;No. But I did take a note of it, let
me see what we discussed | did | &amp;hellip; &amp;quot; and nearly instantly find the note in my
notebook or laptop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, I could probably write about my note taking strategy and formats, as
well as the rules that I&amp;rsquo;ve developed for myself, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t the point of
this article.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to talk about how using a &lt;em>graph database&lt;/em> can improve &lt;strong>your&lt;/strong> note
taking (if you&amp;rsquo;re taking notes on a computer).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="obsidian">Obsidian&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I started to use the &lt;a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian&lt;/a> software to take my notes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was drawn to it for a few reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It used markdown which, to me, is the fastest way to take notes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It had pretty good shortcut keys out of the box&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It allows for extensions to expand the capabilities of the software&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It utilizes a graph database to link notes together&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>That last point is what I want to write about briefly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By leveraging a graph database, Obsidian allows users to link notes together
based on tags rather than on hyper links. In other words, If I write a note such
as, &amp;ldquo;The perceptron is the building block of machine learning,&amp;rdquo; I can reference
it elsewhere by tagging it like &lt;em>#ml #perceptron #&amp;hellip;&lt;/em>. Then, if I ever refernce
something else using the &lt;em>#perceptron&lt;/em> tag and want to see related notes I&amp;rsquo;ve
made using that tag, I can search for &lt;em>#perceptron&lt;/em> and get results both &lt;strong>in
file&lt;/strong> and across &lt;strong>folders and subdirectories&lt;/strong>. It is even possible to get
results from other folders not in the same branch!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty cool searching feature that allows me to spend less time
remembering where I put every note about perceptrons, and spend more time
communicatiing my notes to others. Going back to the computer analogy, I no
longer need to store an array of file paths for each topic, rather, I now just
need to store the keys to a map/dictionary which will return me an array of note
file paths. Storing the keys to this map is so much easier to remember and
utilize than remembering an array (at least for me).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-graph-database">The Graph Database&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So I brought up tagging which is cool, but how does this have to do anything
regarding graph databases?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obsidian automatically adds files and tags to a graph database which allows for
a visual representation of how each file is related to one another. This allows
for (what I call) meta-discovery of knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meta-discovery is the act of finding out how each file relates to one another by
looking at their shared tags. This is of finding out how one subject relates to
another. In practice, it looks like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>I have a note that contains the tags *#ml #perceptron #adaline #linear-seperability*.
Using Obsidian&amp;#39;s graph database visualization, I can see that this particular file talks about those tags.
Now I have 100 files with a thousand tags total.
I can click on a tag and visualize the notes that reference a tag.
I can also click on a note and see what tags it references.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Both of these examples allow me to visualize the relatedness of notes and tags.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="is-it-perfect">Is It Perfect?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>No.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have forgone using technical terms in this article that properly describe
graph databases for the sake of talking about my experience with the tool. There
are many features not present in Obsidian that I wish were availible, such as
clicking on two tags to visualize the paths between each tag.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But Obsidian provides me with a way of referring to notes faster and more
effieciently than I have before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So for that, it&amp;rsquo;s alright in my book.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m doing the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23100daystooffload&amp;amp;src=typed_query">#100DaysToOffload&lt;/a> challenge.
Check &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nick_synovic">my Twitter&lt;/a> for updates!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Twitter, OAuth 2.0, and the Command Line</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/twitter-oauth-and-cli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 09:25:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/posts/twitter-oauth-and-cli/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="preface">Preface&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t use social media that often. I think that it gets in the way of my day
to day life. Like really, I &lt;em>need&lt;/em> to tell everyone that I&amp;rsquo;m eating food right
now? It seems crazy writing that down anyways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But due to an opportunity with Intel, I now have to join the masses. So I
decided to reopen my Twitter account, and realized something right away: I hate
the interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t care about my likes, reccomendations, or the trending news. I have other
ways of getting some of that information. All I want to do is tweet into the
void my thoughts on technology, in a nice, cozy space. And what can be cozier
than the command line!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s how this project got started: I want to tweet rapidly from the command
line. &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>No problem&lt;/em>,&amp;rdquo; I naively thought, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>I&amp;rsquo;ll just use Twitter&amp;rsquo;s REST API. It
can&amp;rsquo;t be that hard.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; But alas, it was a beast far greater than I ever expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="completing-the-first-leg">Completing the First Leg&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As an end user, I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced the benefits of OAuth 2.0. As a developer
though, I&amp;rsquo;ve never had to handle client side access via OAuth 2.0. I&amp;rsquo;ve also
never had to implement OAuth 2.0 into an app as an authentication layer, but
that&amp;rsquo;s a future project problem. However, I do have lots of experience with
accessing web APIs and web scraping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With my history of experience I figured this should be a cake walk. And
reviewing Twitter&amp;rsquo;s OAuth 2.0 diagram, it seemed relatively straight forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://nsynovic.dev/twitterOAuthDiagram.png" alt="Twitter OAuth 2.0 Diagram" title="Twitter OAuth 2.0 Diagram">
&lt;a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/docs/authentication/oauth-2-0/authorization-code">&lt;em>Twitter OAuth 2.0 Diagram&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But nothing is ever as easy as it seems. Following the documentation, I created
my OAuth 2.0 client ID and Secret but I noticed something: I needed a redirect
URL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I don&amp;rsquo;t have a registered webserver that I can send these requests to, I
figured &lt;code>http://localhost:4269&lt;/code> will do. But in testing, it failed. Why? I&amp;rsquo;m not
sure, but upon checking &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/1979559">StackOverflow&lt;/a>,
the answer was really odd: For some reason, Twitter doesn&amp;rsquo;t like sending
requests to &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code>. But they are ok with sending requests to an ip address
that points to &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code>. So I implemented a fix to my OAuth registration and
changed the redirect URL to &lt;code>http://127.0.0.1:4269&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I can send requests to Twitter, thus cmpleting the first leg of the
authentication chain, but I have no way of listening for a response on that
port. This is needed as OAuth 2.0 sends a &lt;code>state&lt;/code> to verify that the request
wasn&amp;rsquo;t tampered and a &lt;code>code&lt;/code> that act as authentication token to for generating
an access token (the end goal). This is where I gulped in fear as I opened the
Python documentation for
&lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/socket.html">&lt;code>socket&lt;/code>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sidebar-did-i-mention-that-im-wrting-this-in-python">Sidebar: Did I Mention That I&amp;rsquo;m Wrting This in Python?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Yeah&amp;hellip; maybe not the smartest decision. Twitter and other developers have
solved this problem in other languages. But I have two good reasons for doing
so:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Most of the work that I do is in Python. As I may need to access an OAuth 2.0
endpoint at some point, I want to make sure that I have the knowledge to do
so.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There is more complexity in learning a new programming language than learning
a new feature of a language you know. I&amp;rsquo;d rather not spend cycles figuring
out syntax when I could be working.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="socket">Socket&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/socket.html">&lt;code>socket&lt;/code>&lt;/a> is a Python module
that provides an interface into the
&lt;a href="https://manpages.debian.org/bullseye/manpages-dev/socket.2.en.html">C socket library&lt;/a>.
It allows for a developer to create low level connections to both local and
external ports to send and recieve communication. It also inherits all of the
blocking problems that handling socket communications has as well (more on that
later).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did also look for other libraries prior to working with &lt;code>sockets&lt;/code>, but I
decided against the other options. This was due to when they were last updated
(most of them were years ago) and that I wanted to challenge myself with
learning a new skill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m going to skip a lot of the debugging here as that&amp;rsquo;s boring and jump right
into the meat of this. Here was my task:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Listen to port 4269 on 127.0.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> When data is recieved, store it as a &lt;code>ByteStreamIO&lt;/code> object&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Here is my code for accomplishing these tasks You can also view the code on
GitHub as well
&lt;a href="https://github.com/NicholasSynovic/hushtweet/blob/main/hushtweet/utils/server.py">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">from&lt;/span> io &lt;span style="color:#f92672">import&lt;/span> BytesIO
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">import&lt;/span> socket
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">def&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">getAuthToken&lt;/span>(ip: str &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;127.0.0.1&amp;#34;&lt;/span>, port: int &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">4269&lt;/span>) &lt;span style="color:#f92672">-&amp;gt;&lt;/span> BytesIO:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> data: BytesIO &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> BytesIO()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">with&lt;/span> socket&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>socket(socket&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>AF_INET, socket&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>SOCK_STREAM) &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">as&lt;/span> server:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> server&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>setsockopt(socket&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>SOL_SOCKET, socket&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>SO_REUSEADDR, &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">1&lt;/span>) &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># Reuse port&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> server&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>bind((ip, port))
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> server&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>listen()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> conn, addr &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> server&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>accept()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">with&lt;/span> conn:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> data&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>write(conn&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>recv(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">4096&lt;/span>))
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> conn&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>close()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> server&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>close()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">return&lt;/span> data
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>With this function, I accomplished the above tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Listen to port 4269 on 127.0.0.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> When data is recieved, store it as a &lt;code>ByteStreamIO&lt;/code> object&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>But there is a problem with this code. And it is a problem that system&amp;rsquo;s
engineers have had to deal with since forever: Blocking.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="blocking">Blocking&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Blocking is when an application is halted, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t close, because it is
waiting for a task to accomplis that never will. The blocking problem with
&lt;code>socket&lt;/code>s programming is that if you are waiting for data to be recieved, you
won&amp;rsquo;t know when the entire data stream arrives. To solve this, I implemented a
&lt;em>trivial&lt;/em> solution by accepting the first 4096 bytes (4 kilobytes) of data.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>data&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>write(conn&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>recv(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">4096&lt;/span>))
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>In testing, this buffer is nearly 4 times larger than what it needs to be. But
as this isn&amp;rsquo;t meant to be the most performant code ever written, I&amp;rsquo;m just going
to ignore that observation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then the question is, &amp;ldquo;What is the actual/correct solution to this problem?&amp;rdquo;
It&amp;rsquo;s to put a termination charachter or accepted stopping charachter to the end
of the message so that the recipient knows when to stop listenting for more
data. The problem is that there is not a general, accepted termination
charachter that is implemented in &lt;strong>every&lt;/strong> message or system. Twitter, from
what I can tell, in their OAuth 2.0 implementation does not add a stopping
charachter to their messages to the redirect URL. Because of this, I ended up
having to create a large buffer of data to hold the recieved data even though
that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be necessary if I knew what the termination charachter was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Is this the best solution? No. The best solution would be a webserver that
listens for the HTTP GET request that Twitter sends to the redirect URL and
parsing it from there. I &lt;em>think&lt;/em> this is similar to what
&lt;a href="https://rclone.org/">&lt;code>rclone&lt;/code>&lt;/a> does to handle thier OAuth 2.0 requests.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, does it work? Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Was it worth it? Eh?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was definitely useful to learn a little bit of &lt;code>socket&lt;/code>s programming and to
work with OAuth 2.0. But I don&amp;rsquo;t think that I&amp;rsquo;ll be going down this route again
unless absolutely necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m doing the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23100daystooffload&amp;amp;src=typed_query">#100DaysToOffload&lt;/a> challenge.
Check &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nick_synovic">my Twitter&lt;/a> for updates!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>