<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>discussion on Nicholas M. Synovic</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/categories/discussion/</link><description>Recent content in discussion on Nicholas M. Synovic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Nicholas M. Synovic</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 10:41:18 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nsynovic.dev/categories/discussion/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A summary of Efficient Computer Vision for Embedded Systems by George K. Thiruvathukal and Yung-Hsiang Lu</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/efficient-computer-vision-for-embedded-systems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 10:41:18 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/efficient-computer-vision-for-embedded-systems/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-summary-of-a-summary-of-efficient-computer-vision-for-embedded-systems-0">A summary of &lt;em>A summary of Efficient Computer Vision for Embedded Systems&lt;/em> [0]&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>George K. Thiruvathukal and Yung-Hsiang Lu IEEE Computer Volume 55; Issue 4,
2022 &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/MC.2022.3145677">DOI&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>For the summary of the paper, go to the &lt;a href="#summary">Summary&lt;/a> section of this
article.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-summary-of-a-summary-of-efficient-computer-vision-for-embedded-systems-0">A summary of &lt;em>A summary of Efficient Computer Vision for Embedded Systems&lt;/em> [0]&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary">Summary&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#lpcvc">LPCVC&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#lpcvc-research">LPCVC Research&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#citations">Citations&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Disclosure: Both George K. Thiruvathukal and Yung-Hsiang Lu are mentors,
colleagues, and friends of mine. Disclosure: I am a student organizer of the
2023 Low Power Computer Vision competition.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Computer Vision (CV) research and development is encouraged through competitions
that measure the accuracy of models for cash prizes. However, as more CV
technologies are being pushed towards the edge, power and computational
efficiency of these models become increasingly more important. Therefore, the
&lt;em>IEEE Low Power Computer Vision Challenge&lt;/em> (LPCVC) [1], formerly the &lt;em>Low
Power Image Recognition Challenge&lt;/em>, was created to encourage researchers to
develop efficient low power solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lpcvc">LPCVC&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Why did you participate in LPCVC?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Researchers participate to develop and formalize techniques for running machine
learning on the edge. This could be designing new hardware to accelerate CV
models and/or validating optimization and software techniques developign new CV
models. Additionally, this challenge encourages the discovery of new research
topics to pursue.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>How is LPCVC relevant to activities in the IEEE Computer Society&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The development and support of CV research is crucial the Computer Society&amp;rsquo;s
mission. The technical community, &lt;em>Technical Community on Pattern Analysis and
Machine Intelligence&lt;/em> [2], exists to promote the development of research and
solutions to problems surrounding and involving CV. Furthermore, the &lt;em>Computer
Vision and Pattern Recognition&lt;/em> (CVPR) confrence [3] is currently IEEE&amp;rsquo;s most
influential confrence as ranked by &lt;em>Guide2Research&lt;/em> [4].&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lpcvc-research">LPCVC Research&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Why is research in LPCV important?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As AI on the edge becomes more ubiquotous and desired by consumers, academic
research my provide industry with potential solutions to implement on the edge.
Furthermore, there exists a hardware challenge alongside the software challenge
of deploying LPCV solutions on edge. Thus hardware focussed research must occur
to assist in LPCV optimizations. Hardware devices such as GPUs, CPUs, and Neural
Processing Units (NPUs) need to be designed and optimized (w.r.t hardware and
software) to support CV applications on the edge. Therefore, LPCV research
involves the union of power efficient designs and optimizations of both the
deployment hardware and solution software.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Can you describe one (or several) &amp;ldquo;grand challenges&amp;rdquo; using CV; the solutions
will significantly change the world, but are they far beyond today&amp;rsquo;s
technologies?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Better smart systems (e.g smart homes, retail, factory, transportation, farming,
etc.) and prediction of natural disasters and phenonemon by utilizing many data
points can be possible through LPCV.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>If you have unlimited resources, what would you like to see in the area of
LPCV?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Researchers in the space are looking for new datasets, challenges, and problem
specific competitions to advance research in LPCV.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="citations">Citations&lt;/h2>
Citations availible at https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/efficient-computer-vision-for-embedded-systems/</description></item></channel></rss>