<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>scientific programming on Nicholas M. Synovic</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/categories/scientific-programming/</link><description>Recent content in scientific programming on Nicholas M. Synovic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Nicholas M. Synovic</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 21:34:36 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nsynovic.dev/categories/scientific-programming/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A summary of Supercomputing In Python With Legate by Michael Bauer et al.</title><link>https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/supercomputing-in-python-with-legate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 21:34:36 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/supercomputing-in-python-with-legate/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-summary-of-supercomputing-in-python-with-legate">A summary of &lt;em>Supercomputing In Python With Legate&lt;/em>&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Michael Bauer et al. IEEE Computing Edge, October 2022 DOI [0]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-summary-of-supercomputing-in-python-with-legate">A summary of &lt;em>Supercomputing In Python With Legate&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary">Summary&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#supercomputing-with-numpy">Supercomputing With Numpy&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#programming-system">Programming System&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#composable-ecosystem">Composable Ecosystem&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#citations">Citations&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Numpy and Pandas are software packages that aid in the development of
mathematical software because their notations mimic that of scientific and
mathematical notation. However, neither package scales to modern HPC. Thus
Legate was developed to mimic the interfaces that both Numpy and Pandas provide
while being able to scale to many computing resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="supercomputing-with-numpy">Supercomputing With Numpy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Numpy syntax is compact and able to concisely express mathematical operations.
Additionally, Numpy operations offer themselves to parallelization easily.
However, vanilla Numpy doesn&amp;rsquo;t natively support these parallelization
optimizations. Therefore a number of efforts exist to implement these
optimizations. Legate supports these operations and fall backs to single-core
performance when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Legate defines a common data model that can be used to expand Numpy&amp;rsquo;s memory
allocation and library extensions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Legate&amp;rsquo;s extensions to Numpy provide access to data parallel operations that
vanilla Numpy and similar alternatives to Legate don&amp;rsquo;t offer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="programming-system">Programming System&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Legate is built on top of Legion, which acts as a dynamic programming system for
HPC. When a call is made from Legate, Legion is able to interpret this code and
distribute it to many nodes. Legion may also reorder Legate calls for better
performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was done to avoid compiling Legate-Numpy code into an optimized program for
HPC.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="composable-ecosystem">Composable Ecosystem&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Legate aims to be a building block for other Numpy based libraries to be based
off of. As an example of this, Legate Pandas was created as a Pandas alternative
complete with parallelization optimizations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An advantage of building off of Legate and Legion is that the communication and
protocol layer already exist, thereby allowing developers to easily extend these
applications to their respective purposes.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="citations">Citations&lt;/h2>
Citations availible at https://nsynovic.dev/summaries/supercomputing-in-python-with-legate/</description></item></channel></rss>